From An Age of Conflict...A Film For The Ages!
The Last Valley is a history, war, drama film directed by James Clavell.
People in a small German village in the last valley to remain untouched by the devastating Thirty
Years' War try to exist in peace with a group of soldiers occupying the valley.
The Captain, played by Michael Caine.
Vogel, played by Omar Sharif.
Erica, played by Florinda Bolkan.
Gruber, played by Nigel Davenport.
Father Sebastian, played by Per Oscarsson.
Inge, played by Madeleine Hinde.
The Last Valley is a 1971 film written and directed by James Clavell, an
historical drama set during the Thirty Years' War (1618–1648).
While war ravages in the southern principalities of the Holy Roman Empire, a mercenary leader
(Michael Caine) and a teacher (Omar Sharif) stumble upon a valley untouched by the war.
Based upon the novel The Last Valley (1959), by J.
Pick, the cinematic version of The Last Valley was the final feature film photographed with the
Todd-AO 70 mm widescreen process until it was revived to make the film Baraka in 1991.
The film explores themes of germany, 17th century, war.
The tone is emotional.